Wallis Williams

Nashville, TN | 615.557.6006 | williamswallise@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio Site

Summary

Agile Product Owner at Cigna for Verint speech analytics software, former Quality Assurance analyst for QNXT web application configuration, and software engineering bootcamp graduate - with 13 years health insurance industry experience and 9 years Microsoft SQL experience.

Skills and Certifications

- SQL: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL Workbench, Toad Data Point, Oracle SQL
- Programming Languages and Web Services: C#, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, REST APIs
- IDEs: Microsoft Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code
- Frameworks: ASP.NET MVC. .NET Core
- Version Control: Git and GitHub
- Cloud: AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Software Configuration Quality Assurance, Systems Development Life-Cycle
- TriZetto QNXT Claims Processing web application, Healthcare Claims Testing
- Atlassian Confluence, Hyland OnBase Unity Client, Microsoft Office Suite
- Skyscanner Front-End Software Engineering Job Simulation on Forage September 2023
- Microsoft Report Builder

Software Development Projects

Portfolio Website | HTML, CSS, Visual Studio Code

Organizing Application | ASP.NET MVC, C#, Dapper, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Visual Studio

Created a CRUD app for organization-related tasks and integrated a Bootstrap theme

CRUD Inventory Website | ASP.NET MVC, C#, Dapper, HTML, CSS, JSON, SQL, Visual Studio

Wrote C# functions which allow users to perform CRUD functions on items in a MySQL database

CSV Parsing and Geolocation Console Application | .NET Core, C#, LINQ, xUnit, Visual Studio

- Parsed data from CSV file containing geolocations to determine which are farthest apart
- Wrote xUnit tests to apply Test-Driven Development

Weather Application | .NET Core, C#, API, Visual Studio

• Used C# and Newtonsoft.Json NuGet package to create this app, which displays weather for requested city by calling Open Weather Map API

Education

TrueCoders | Full Stack Software Engineering Bootcamp | View Certificate

11/2021 - 11/2022

Trinity University | Bachelor of Arts, English

8/2004 - 5/2008

Work Experience

<u>Cigna</u> | Agile Product Owner Advisor, Speech Analytics (Band 4)

2/2024 - Present

- Utilize Verint's advanced speech analytics software as a member of the Enterprise Operations Verint Business
 Product Ownership team in the Global Digital and Analytics Department to enhance customer service quality and
 optimize interactions with customer, aiming to improve customer satisfaction and increase operational efficiency by
 leveraging Verint's AI capabilities
- Create SQL queries in Microsoft SQL Server to access Microsoft databases and Toad Data Point to Oracle
 databases in Cigna's electronic data warehouse, enhancing data retrieval efficiency and supporting business
 intelligence initiatives related to Verint Real Time and Post-Call Speech Analytics and Text/Chat Analytics; employ
 techniques such as joins, concatenation, subqueries, unions, and temp tables to maximize query performance and
 extract insights from complex datasets
- Leverage Microsoft Report Builder to filter datasets, generate reports, and troubleshoot issues for business partners, contributing to improved data accessibility and decision-making processes
- Apply Agile principles, such as iterative processes, root cause analysis, effective communication, customer collaboration, and the delivery of minimum viable products

Cigna Medicare | Configuration QA and Testing Advisor (Band 4)

1/2019 - 2/2024

- Wrote SQL queries to QA configuration changes made in the QNXT claims processing web application
- Led the QNXT Configuration Cleanup project which monitors for configuration errors in QNXT to improve claim
 adjudication accuracy. Responsibilities included: writing SQL queries to identify errors in configuration data,
 leading meetings with stakeholders and management, coordinating efforts, and prioritizing needs. Submitted over
 275 cleanup Configuration Change Requests ("CCRs") to correct configuration issues in QNXT.
- Collaborated with development team who developed my SQL queries into SSIS reports to enhance efficiency of the Configuration Cleanup process
- Managed Configuration Documentation efforts for Systems Analyst and QA Analyst teams, comprising over 75
 team members. Utilized Atlassian Confluence and SharePoint to create and organize documentation to streamline
 processes, enhance configuration accuracy, and ensure the groups are well-informed about new processes and
 updates to existing processes.
- Created and updated test cases and test plans in Excel; created QA test case templates for the team
- Evaluated ticket accuracy as part of Change Control Board to determine if changes should be approved to Production environment or failed back for corrections to be made
- Identified potential enhancements to QA process during Root Cause Analysis meetings
- Conducted training for new employees; coached QA team on process updates, SQL tips, and QA strategies
- Completed Pre-QA, Configuration QA, and/or Production QA on over 950 tickets ("Configuration Change Requests")

Cigna Medicare | Configuration QA and Testing Specialist (Band 3)

5/2016 -12/2018

- Promoted to Band 3 based on taking on increasingly complex assignments
- Developed QNXT configuration cleanup project, which use SQL queries to detect common configuration issues and improves claims payment accuracy
- Validated systems analysts' Excel templates (containing data to be loaded by development team to QNXT) to ensure they were correct, complete, and formatted properly

<u>Cigna Medicare</u> | Business Analysis Senior Associate (Band 2)

2/2015 - 4/2016

- Wrote and executed manual QA test cases for QNXT configuration change tickets (which include building and updating provider contracts, benefit plans, claim rules/edits, and fee schedules), using SQL to retrieve backend data
- Analyzed data to confirm it aligned with documentation, scope of business need, and expected results
- Gave updates on tasks during daily scrum/stand-up meetings

Cigna Medicare | Eligibility Analyst Senior Associate (Band 2)

10/2013 -2/2015

 Selected to be part of project teams to: review business requirements documents and process flows, define report specifications, map processes, and update policies and procedures